<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nautilus KAD on Pierre Aronnax</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/v.0.1.0/kad/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nautilus KAD on Pierre Aronnax</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2025- Nautilus</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 16:12:37 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/docs/v.0.1.0/kad/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What Is Nautilus KAD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/v.0.1.0/kad/what-is-nautilus-kad/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 16:12:37 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/v.0.1.0/kad/what-is-nautilus-kad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nautilus KAD is a Rust-based Kademlia Distributed Hash Table (DHT) implementation, designed for decentralized, efficient, and fault-tolerant peer-to-peer networks. It enables peer discovery, distributed storage, and efficient node routing by leveraging the Kademlia algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Architecture</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/v.0.1.0/kad/architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 16:12:37 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/v.0.1.0/kad/architecture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nautilus KAD is a Rust-based Kademlia Distributed Hash Table (DHT) implementation, designed for decentralized peer-to-peer networking, efficient routing, and distributed storage. It enables scalable, fault-tolerant, and low-latency network communication, making it ideal for Web3 applications, decentralized storage, and P2P networks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nautilus KAD vs. Others</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/v.0.1.0/kad/nautilus-kad-vs.-others/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 16:12:37 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/v.0.1.0/kad/nautilus-kad-vs.-others/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While there are multiple Kademlia-based DHT implementations, Rust currently only has libp2p-kad, which is tightly integrated with the libp2p framework, making it difficult to use independently. Nautilus KAD was developed to address this gap by providing a standalone, modular, and high-performance Kademlia implementation that is not constrained by external dependencies, enabling greater flexibility and broader applicability in decentralized networks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roadmap</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/v.0.1.0/kad/roadmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 16:12:37 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/v.0.1.0/kad/roadmap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nautilus KAD is a functional Rust-based Kademlia DHT that supports:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Decentralized Peer Discovery – Nodes can locate and connect with peers dynamically.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;XOR Distance-Based Routing – Efficient node lookups using logarithmic search complexity.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Asynchronous Networking – Built with Tokio for non-blocking peer interactions.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Message Serialization – Compact, efficient messages using bincode + serde.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Basic Data Storage &amp;amp; Retrieval – Nodes can store and fetch values via &lt;code&gt;Store&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;FindValue&lt;/code&gt; queries.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;limitations--areas-for-improvement&#34;&gt;Limitations &amp;amp; Areas for Improvement&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While the core functionality is in place, there are several areas requiring enhancement:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
